Contact

kogreen@texaschildrens.org

www.linkedin.com/in/kathy-green-13826519 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing

Pediatrics

Inpatient

Certifications

Certified Pediatric Nurse

Kathy Green

Staff Nurse Texas Children's Hospital

Houston, Texas Area

Summary

I am passionate about...

Specialties:

Pediatrics

NIH Research

Lean Six Sigma Green Belt Certification

2014 Treasurer Elect International Association of Clinical Research

Nurses

2015 Treasurer International Association of Clinical Research

Nurses

Volunteer Houston Livestock Show and Rodeo 1996-present

Experience

Texas Children's Hospital 30 years 1 month

Staff Nurse

May 2014 - Present (6 years 1 month)

Allergy and Immunology Clinic

Staff nurse for the A&I infusion suite. My main focus is infusions of IVIG, Pentamidine and other IV drugs. I also facilitate food/drug allergy challenges.

Nurse Manager

2010 - May 2014 (4 years)

Clinical Research Center

I currently manage and inpatient and outpatient pediatric research unit at Texas Chidlren's Hospital. We have over 100 active research protocols for which we provide primary nursing care related to the needs of each of those research protocols.

Twenty four hour responsibility for research unit that provides nursing support for Pediatric and Adult research. Responsibilities include budgeting, management of staff, review of protocol safety, inter/intradepartmental communications and preparation for competitive National Institutes of Health

Page 1 of 3

grant renewal. Unit has approximately 2000 outpatient, 6000 scatterbed and 200 inpatient visits a year.

Assitant Director of Nursing 2006 - 2010 (4 years)

General Clinical Research Center/Neurology Neurosurgery

Provide 24-hour accountability for clinical, administrative and human resources activities. Ensures delivery of high quality, developmentally appropriate patient and family centered care at the unit level.

Partners with staff, medical and unit leadership to ensure clinical excellence within a family centered care environment. Demonstrates fiscal accountability including preparing and managing the budget. Assistant Director for the Finance Pillar for Acute Care. Identifies, facilitates and participates in performance improvement projects enhancing and ensuring safe patient care including coordinating projects that centered on new patient care processes for Neurology and Neurosurgery patients.

Provides leadership and development for unit leadership team and staff to achieve goals. Facilitates community outreach and presentations. Assistant Director representative for Excel +.

Assistant Director of Nursing 2004 - 2010 (6 years)

General Clinical Research Center

Twenty four hour responsibility for research unit that provides nursing support for Pediatric and Adult research. Responsibilities include budgeting, management of staff, review of protocol safety, inter/intradepartmental communications and preparation for competitive National Institutes of Health grant renewal. Unit has approximately 3800 outpatient, 6000 scatterbed and 600 inpatient visits a year.

Unit Educator

2004 - 2004 (less than a year)

Rapid Treatment Area Emergency Room

Provided staff education around a variety of topics in Emergency Medicine. Coordinated required training and skills check off. Created education documents for the new documentation system.

Staff Nurse 2003 - 2004 (1 year)

Rapid Treatment Area Emergency Room

Staff Nurse in an Emergency Room Observation Unit.

Page 2 of 3

Assistant Director of Nursing 1998 - 2003 (5 years)

Allergy and Immunology

Assistant Director of Nursing for the outpatient section of Allergy and Immunology. Coordinated national HIV and Immunology research protocols including IRB submission, regualtory review and daily study management. Daily management of outpatient Allergy and Immunology clinic including immunotherapy.

Nurse Manager 1994 - 1998 (4 years) 4th floor

Nurse Manager for daily operations on a pediatric Pulmonary, Edocrine and Adoolescent Medicine unit.

Staff Nurse May 1990 - 1994 (4 years) 4th Floor

Staff Nurse, Charge Nurse, Preceptor on a Pulmonary, Adolescent Medicine and Edocrine unit.

Education

Texas Woman's University

MBA, Business Administration and Management, General · (2006 - 2007)

The University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston BSN, Nursing · (1996 - 1997)

Grayson County College ADN, Nursing (1988 - 1990)